Hsiao Wen Yi

☑ s101062219@gmail.com

in Linkedin

Github

Google Schalor

I am a research engineer in Audio/Music/CV/DSP with strong knowledge in AI/ML/DL. I do **research** (>1K citations), and love to code and share (>2.5K stars on Github).

Expertise - Music Information Research (MIR): Generation, Synthesis, Separation, Transcription.

Expertise - Computer Vision (CV): Talking Photo Generation, Lipsync.

Work Experiences

2023.02 - Present

Research Engineer (Senior), Taiwan AILabs

2019.04 - 2023.02

Research Engineer, Taiwan AILabs

Education

2022 – 2023 Ph.D. Communication Engineer, National Taiwan University, stopped.

Advisor: Yi-Hsuan Yang

2016 – 2018 M.Sc. Computer Science, National Tsing Hua University.

Thesis: Automatic Symbolic Music Generation Based on Convolutional GANs.

Advisor: Yi-Hsuan Yang

2012 – 2016 **B.Sc. Computer Science, National Tsing Hua University.**

Publications

Conference Proceedings

- Y. H. Lan, W. Y. Hsiao, and et al., "Musicongen: Rhythm and chord control for transformer-based text-to-music generation," in *Proceedings of International Society on Music Information Retrieval (ISMIR)*, 2024. OURL: https://arxiv.org/html/2407.15060v1.
- Y. T. Yeh, **W. Y. Hsiao**, and et al., "Hyper recurrent neural network: Condition mechanisms for black-box audio effect modeling," in *Proceedings of International Conference on Digital Audio Effects* (DAFX), 2024.
- Y. Chen, **W. Y. Hsiao**, and et al., "Towards automatic transcription of polyphonic electric guitar music: A new dataset and a multi-loss transformer model," in *Proceedings of E Int. Conf. Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP)*, 2022. URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2202.09907.
- W. Y. Hsiao, D. Y. Wu, and et al., "DDSP-based singing vocoders: A new subtractive-based synthesizer and a comprehensive evaluation," in *Proceedings of International Society on Music Information Retrieval* (ISMIR), 2022. OURL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2208.04756.
- C. Y. Chiu, J. Ching, **W. Y. Hsiao**, and et al., "Source separation-based data augmentation for improved joint beat and downbeat tracking," in *Proceedings of European Signal Processing Conference (EUSIPCO)*, 2021. OURL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2106.08703.
- W. Y. Hsiao and et al., "Compound word transformer: Learning to compose full-song music over dynamic directed hypergraphs," in *Proceedings of AAAI Conf. Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)*, 2021. URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2101.02402.
- Y. H. Chen, Y. S. Huang, **W. Y. Hsiao**, and et al., "Automatic composition of guitar tabs by transformers and groove modeling," in *Proceedings of International Society on Music Information Retrieval (ISMIR)*, 2020. **9** URL: https://arxiv.org/pdf/2008.01431.

- C. Y. Chiu, **W. Y. Hsiao**, and et al., "Mixing-specific data augmentation techniques for improved blind violin/piano source separation," in *IEEE Int. Workshop on Multimedia Signal Processing (MMSP)*, 2020. URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2008.02480.
- **W. Y. Hsiao**, H. W. Dong, and et al., "Musegan: Multi-track sequential generative adversarial networks for symbolic music generation and accompaniment," in *Proceedings of AAAI Conf. Artificial Intelligence* (AAAI), 2018. **Ourl**: https://arxiv.org/abs/1709.06298.

Journal Articles

Y. C. Yeh, **W. Y. Hsiao**, and et al., "Automatic melody harmonization with triad chords: A comparative study," *Journal of New Music Research*, 2019. OURL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2001.02360.

Skills

Languages English, Chinese

Coding Python: Pytorch, Tensorflow C++: JUCE, Eigen, Libtorch

System Git, Docker, k8s

Miscellaneous Experience

Peer Review Experience

2018 Helping Paper Review@ACM Multimedia (ACMMM)

Helping Paper Review@International Conference on Multimedia and Expo (IEEE ICME)

Helping Journal Review@Neural Computing and Applications (NCAA)

Awards and Achievements

Performance, Beethoven - Piano Concerto No.3

Performance, Kapustin - Concert Etude Op.40 No.6

2018 Silver Award, 9th Merry Electronics Master Thesis Award

2014 Vice Director of Piano Club

Open Source Projects

1.8k stars MuseGAN, Official Repository for AAAI18 Paper

265 stars Compound Word Transformer, Official Repository for AAAI21 Paper

248 stars DDSP Singing Vocoders, Official Repository for ISMIR22 Paper

226 stars Miditoolkit, Popular Python Package (used by >300 projects) for Handling MIDI IO

128 stars Symbolic Musical Datasets, A Collection of Symbolic Music Dataset in Various Formats

108 stars Lead Sheet Dataset, A Collection of Lead Sheet Dataset in Various Formats

94 stars ReaRender, A Python Package for Automatic Rendering using REAPER

52 stars | SF Segmenter, A Python Package for Structure Analysis

Products and Internal Projects

- AI Music Platform Yating Studio
- AI Avatar Yating Virtual Anchor